sgmjournals.org 2016-11-27

# Privacy Policy | Microbiology Society

###  Who we are

The Microbiology Society is a registered charity in England and Wales (no. 264017), a charity registered in Scotland (no. SC039250) and a company limited by guarantee, registered in England (no. 1039582). We are registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office (no. Z5802841) in the UK under the Data Protection Act 1998.

Membership and fulfilment services are provided to the Microbiology Society by IRIS NFP through Integra CRM.

###  What we collect

The types of personal information we collect may include your title, first name, surname, gender, date of birth, your qualifications, home and work contact details (telephone, fax, street address, email address, credit card details or bank details) and your mailing address. We may also collect information relating to your employment, including where you are currently employed, your job title, areas of interest/expertise and your job function if this is relevant to your membership. In applications for some categories of membership we ask you to identify a referee and to provide contact information for them. When purchasing a product, your credit card details are also collected, and are temporarily stored until we have processed your order.

###  How we handle your personal information

The Microbiology Society respects the privacy of its members and website users, and aims to act consistently with the Data Protection Act, and the eight principles of data protection.

Generally, the Microbiology Society collects personal information directly from you or via the CRM. For example, we collect personal information when you:

  * Fill out and submit a Membership application form
  * Submit any other information in connection with your application for membership or the purchase of products and services
  * Register for a journal subscription
  * Make an enquiry via a web form
  * Apply for a bursary or grant
  * Register to attend an event

###  Why we collect information

We collect personal data to administer our activities, products, services or grants and bursaries.

###  Maintaining the accuracy of data

Members can correct or update personal data by [logging in](https://secure.sgm.ac.uk/membersarea/login/login.asp?type=EXTRANET), or by contacting the Society by email: [members@microbiologysociety.org](mailto:members@microbiologysociety.org).

###  Payment and bank details

Any information provided by you in connection with a direct debit payment or transaction regarding your credit or debit card numbers, expiry date and billing or delivery address will be used by us to process the transaction.

Bank details are collected during grant and bursary applications, to ensure rapid payment is made to successful applicants. This information will be held for as long as necessary to fulfil the stated purpose, and then permanently deleted.

###  Use and disclosure

The Microbiology Society’s policy is not to disclose any personal information that we hold on you to any unrelated third party, except where you have given your express consent for us to do so or where required by law.

Arrangements are occasionally made with suppliers of goods and services (such as other scientific societies for their mailings to be sent to members). All material is carefully vetted and the mailing list is never released to third parties. The Microbiology Society may use your email address for the purpose of notifying you about products, services, events or activities of relevance to you. If you tell us that you do not wish us to use your personal information for a particular purpose, we will not do so.

Email addresses of people who place electronic orders are used for reply purposes only unless specifically stated otherwise. We also collect email addresses from people who subscribe to our newsletter. If you do not want to receive emails from us in the future please unsubscribe using the link provided.

Personal information collected on this website will be used only for the purpose stated (such as the processing of grant applications) and such information will be held for as long as necessary to fulfil the stated purpose. Personal data collected during the process of membership application will be kept indefinitely, in a secure database, for the purpose of lapsed membership campaigns.

The Microbiology Society (or its committee members/representatives) may, from time to time, email you with additional information considered to be relevant to your professional/scientific interests, but only to those who have given their agreement to receiving such communications.

###  Security

Information that you supply to the Microbiology Society is  held securely and strict security procedures are followed to prevent unauthorised access or use.

###  Information to improve our site

We also collect information automatically about your visit to our site. This information is used to help us follow browsing preferences on our site so that we can regularly improve our website and enable more advanced features of our website. For more information please see our [cookies policy](http://www.sgm.ac.uk/about-this-site/cookies/index.cfm).

###  Access to personal information

You can seek access to the personal information we hold about you, by contacting us. You should include your name, address and telephone number. The Microbiology Society may charge a fee for responding to an access request. If the information we hold about you is inaccurate, incomplete or out-dated, please update the information using our [online system](https://secure.sgm.ac.uk/membersarea/login/login.asp?type=EXTRANET) or inform us so that we can correct it.

###  How to contact us:

Microbiology Society  
Tel: +44 (0)20 7685 2400
